welcome back to another shotcut video
欢迎回到另一个截图视频
editing tutorial in this video we're
编辑教程在这段视频中我们
going to be looking at the green screen
将会看到绿色屏幕
chroma key feature and taking out a
色度键功能和取出一个
certain color and then compositing it
特定的颜色 然后合成它
over a different video so should be a
在不同的视频上所以应该是
lot of fun what we're gonna do first is
有趣的是 我们首先要做的是
click here and go to add video track and
单击此处并转至添加视频曲目和
then add video track we need to have two
然后添加视频轨道 我们需要有两个
tracks because we need a video for our
因为我们需要一段录像带
background I'm just going to choose this
背景我只想选择这个
one in this case so whatever's on this
在这种情况下是一个 所以不管这上面有什么
lower track will appear in the
较低的轨道将出现在
background and then whatever we place on
背景 然后无论我们放在什么上面
top of it so in this case it'll be our
所以在这种情况下 它将是我们的
clip with a green or blue screen or a
带有绿色或蓝色屏幕的剪辑或
consistent color that we want to remove
我们要删除的一致颜色
and so what we'll do is take out this so
所以我们要做的就是把这个拿出来
if we play it now we see that it's just
如果我们现在播放 我们会发现它只是
the green we're not seeing this
我们看不到的绿色
background like we want it we want to
我们想要的背景 我们想要的
see the jet of course but we don't want
当然是看到飞机了 但我们不想
to see this green we want it to be
为了看到这片绿色 我们希望它是
transparent so to turn it transparent we
所以为了让它变得透明 我们
use the chroma key feature and basically
使用色度键功能 基本上
it's a filter so we add it as under
这是一个过滤器 所以我们将其添加为
video and it's just chroma key there
视频 那里只有色度键
simple and advanced we'll just start
简单和高级 我们只是开始
with simple and we see that by default
使用Simple 我们可以看到默认情况下
since it's it was set up for this green
因为它是为这个果岭而设的
color we can choose a certain color so
颜色我们可以选择某种颜色 所以
this is what it might look like oh
这就是它可能看起来的样子哦
actually we want to black either if we
事实上 我们也想要黑色的 如果我们
choose a weird color that this doesn't
选择一种奇怪的颜色 这不是
have then we kind of see what this
然后我们来看看这是什么
looked like originally and then we can
看起来像原来的样子 然后我们就可以
actually take this eyedropper and select
实际上 拿着这个滴管 选择
this green color to really help it look
这种绿色真的让它看起来很漂亮
more natural there's still a little bit
更自然的 还有一点
of green up here we can see it looks a
在这里我们可以看到它看起来像一个
little bit strange but at least this
有点奇怪 但至少这个
actually isn't too bad so the video
其实还不算太差 所以视频
still playing in the background and then
仍然在背景中播放然后
we also have this jet just flying away
我们还有一架喷气式飞机刚刚飞走
from the house super low to the ground
从超低到地面的房子
and then yeah that's that so I'm not too
然后 是的 就是这样 所以我不会太
bad and then if we want to we can bring
坏的 如果我们想的话我们可以带上
that in and see some of that green that
在那里 看到一些绿色的东西
we don't really would like to adjust a
我们真的不想调整一个
little bit we can adjust and fine-tune
我们可以调整和微调一点
here and see so that kind of makes that
这里 看看 所以这就是为什么
all kind of green in we can adjust until
所有的绿色我们都可以调整 直到
a lot of that green goes away but if we
很多绿色都消失了 但如果我们
go too far we start losing some of our
走得太远 我们开始失去一些我们的
some clarity too so we just adjust there
也有一些清晰度 所以我们只是在那里进行调整
and that looks pretty good
这看起来很不错
yeah not too bad though huh it helps
是啊 还不算太糟 是不是很有帮助
that my video clip if I go back to the
我的视频剪辑如果我回到
source it helps that these video clips
来源：这些视频剪辑有帮助
are the same size
都是一样的大小
I go to properties I see is 1920 by 1080
我去看1920年到1080年的房产
both of them are which makes it nice
他们两个都是 这让人感觉很好
otherwise that jet would be really small
否则那架喷气式飞机就会很小
and I would have to scale it first if it
如果是这样的话 我就得先把它放进去
were smaller than my source of it than
比我的来源还小
my the other video I was compositing it
我的另一个视频我在合成它
against or vice versa so when doing
当这样做时 反之亦然
chroma key it's a good idea to always
色度键始终是个好主意
have your your Clips be the same size
你的夹子是一样大小的吗？
but it's not necessary I mean we can
但没必要 我是说我们可以
always change it in fact what we could
总是尽我们所能去改变它
do if we want this jet to be a little
如果我们想让这架喷气式飞机
bit smaller and just up here in the sky
更小一点 就在天空中
we could now go to filters and apply a
我们现在可以转到筛选器并应用
size what do I do a size and position we
尺码我要做什么尺码和位置
click on this go to filters go to add
单击此转至过滤器转至添加
and we type in size and position so now
现在我们输入大小和位置
we can actually take this and we can
我们真的可以拿到这个 我们可以
resize it and it resizes it with the
调整它的大小 并使用
green screen and we can kind of put it
绿色屏幕 我们可以把它
up here I don't know if this is gonna
在这上面我不知道这会不会
make anything because you didn't look
做任何事都是因为你没有看起来
good or not let's go to the beginning of
好还是不好 让我们从头开始
see now we have the jet just sort of up
看 现在我们有了喷气式飞机
there slowly flying by this part of it
它的这一部分慢慢地飞过
right there so you can do you know
就在那里 这样你就可以知道
multiple and a lot of times you will do
很多很多次你都会这么做
size and position and scale your green
确定绿色区域的大小、位置和比例
screened object because you want it to
屏蔽对象 因为您希望它
just be floating in the middle of your
只是漂浮在你的中间
of your video let's look at doing one
在你的视频中 让我们来看一看
more well let's look at the advanced now
更好的是 我们现在来看看高级的
so I'm going to click on here and delete
所以我要点击这里并删除
and that gets rid of all the effects we
这消除了我们所有的影响
did too and then might as well just
也这么做了 然后干脆
since we're deleting anyway let's bring
既然我们无论如何都要删除 那就让我们
in this is a cool one this door so let's
这是一扇很酷的门 所以让我们
bring in this clip that I'm sure you're
带上这段视频 我敢肯定你是
not sick of yet and let's bring in this
还没有厌倦 让我们把这个带进来
one so what we're gonna do is have this
一 所以我们要做的是用这个
door open and we'll see hopefully
门打开了 我们会看到希望的
someone playing the banjo out on the
有人在外面弹班卓琴
back porch but so we after this green is
后面的门廊 但我们在这个绿色的是
a lot more pale and then that last one
更苍白的 然后是最后一个
we were looking at so let's see how this
我们正在看 所以让我们看看这是如何
works we go to filters we select the
作品我们转到过滤器 我们选择
clip with the door we go to add video
剪辑与我们要去的门添加视频
and we go to let's try now we'll just do
我们去试一试 现在我们就去做
the advanced so we need to pick the
所以我们需要选择先进的
color so we'll grab our I draw
所以我们要抓起我们的I画
and tell it that that shade well look at
告诉它 那个树荫看起来
that pretty good so far so that's the
到目前为止还不错 所以这就是
shade we want and then let's move this
遮挡我们想要的 然后让我们移动这个
video a little bit where is it at so we
视频在哪里 所以我们
go to size and position so let's move
选择合适的尺寸和位置 我们开始行动吧
this over a little bit here so we can Oh
这里有一点 所以我们可以哦
wrong one control let's get rid of size
一个错误的控制让我们摆脱大小
in position there let's come over here
在那里的位置上 我们到这边来
and let's apply a size and position to
让我们将大小和位置应用于
this background video so we go now we
这段背景视频 所以我们现在开始
can move this and have it be back here
我可以把这个搬过来然后放回这里
this is my buddy Reef playing the banjo
这是我的朋友Reef在弹班卓琴
alright so here we go not too bad
好的 我们开始吧 还不算太糟
so this door gets opened and reached out
所以这扇门被打开并伸了出来
here larger-than-life playing banjo ok
在这里弹奏五弦琴 比真人还大
we can make some adjustments on here now
我们现在可以在这里做一些调整
so we come back to this one that has the
所以我们回到这一个 它有
the chroma key and now we can make some
色度键 现在我们可以做一些
adjustments just like we did before on
就像我们以前做的那样进行调整
this simple well now this basically has
这个简单的好 现在这个基本上有
some different ones that we can adjust
一些我们可以调整的不同的
so we can do this one we don't want to
所以我们可以做我们不想做的这件事
start getting rid of that door though so
开始摆脱那扇门吧 尽管如此
we kind of make some changes here to get
我们在这里做了一些改变 以获得
rid of some of that green and some of
去掉一些绿色的和一些
that weird-looking yeah just some
那个看起来怪怪的 对 就是一些
artifacting happening there so we don't
人工制品在那里发生 所以我们不会
we again we don't want to go too much
我们再说一遍 我们不想走太远
and we digest we can apply some lighting
我们消化了我们可以应用一些照明
filters too to kind of match the
过滤器也不能与
lighting since this is done in a studio
照明 因为这是在演播室里完成的
and this one's done out doors oh by the
而这个是在户外完成的 哦 在
way I should just mention both of these
我应该只提到这两件事
clips I got from pixabay so there's some
我从Pixabay那里得到的剪辑 所以有一些
different Clips you can get include the
您可以获得的不同剪辑包括
link it's pixabay.com
链接它是Pixabay.com
and some great open source or very open
以及一些伟大的开源或非常开放的
licensing for getting some nice video
获得一些好视频的许可
clips if you need something to work with
夹子 如果你需要一些东西来工作
oh and then you can change what also
哦 然后你还可以改变什么
other settings you're not exactly sure
您不太确定的其他设置
what these do but see it changes the the
这些做了什么 但看到了它改变了
way this appears so play with some of
这样看起来就像是在玩一些
these settings and see that floor looks
这些设置和查看地板看起来
a little bit strange it's all black
有点奇怪 全是黑色的
there so some of these we can change and
所以我们可以改变其中的一些
make it look a little bit more natural
让它看起来更自然一点
and then this shape kind of just affects
然后这个形状就会影响到
I actually don't know exactly what it
我其实不知道它到底是什么
does but it affects the way the green
但它影响了果岭
screening works
筛选工程
we'll go back to the ellipse maybe there
我们会回到椭圆形 也许在那里
you have it that is doing chroma key in
你有做色调的那个吗？
shot cut actually really not too bad at
投篮切分其实还不算太差
all
全
this invert here actually inverts it the
这里的倒置实际上是将它倒置为
other way around so now we're seeing the
反过来说 现在我们看到
base basically it's like switching these
基本上就像是换了这些
two clips so now we're actually seeing
两个片段所以现在我们实际上看到的是
this part of the green screen
绿屏的这一部分
everything else is masked out but yeah
其他的一切都被掩盖了 但耶
play with that and let me know if you
玩这个 让我知道如果你
have any questions comments below this
如有任何疑问 请在下面发表意见
might be the last shot cut video I do in
可能是我拍摄的最后一个镜头剪辑的视频
a little while but I'll keep adding to
一小会儿 但我会继续增加
as more projects come to mind just so
随着越来越多的项目浮现在脑海中
you know I have been using shot cut to
你知道我一直在用镜头剪辑
compile all of these video this video
将所有这些视频汇编成此视频
tutorial series and there's been some
系列教程 已经有了一些
pluses and minuses you know if you've
优缺点你知道你有没有
been watching the last couple videos
我在看最近的几个视频
we've had some crashes I'm haven't been
我们有过一些撞车事故 我还没有经历过
really impressed with the stability of
非常令人印象深刻的稳定性
of shot cut but what I will say is the
但我要说的是
rendering is very quick so it's actually
渲染速度非常快 所以实际上
faster rendering when we go to export
在我们进行导出时渲染速度更快
our video the rendering is much quicker
我们的视频渲染速度快得多
than kdenlive it takes full advantage or
比起kdenlive 它充分利用了
a lot more advantage of GPU and CPU
GPU和CPU的更多优势
whereas for the time being kdenlive is
鉴于目前kdenlive是
only cpu rendering at least without some
只有CPU渲染 至少没有一些
workarounds so I do like the rendering I
变通办法 所以我确实喜欢渲染
love the simplicity of the interface I
我喜欢界面的简单性
think for like your grandma this would
想像你奶奶这样的人来说这会
be the best open source program she can
成为她能做的最好的开源程序
use for video editing but when you do
用于视频编辑 但当您这样做时
get into the upper end of some of the
进入一些的高端
different effects transitions filters I
不同的效果过渡滤镜I
think you can want to go over towards
我想你可以想过去
kdenlive or something like The DaVinci
kdenlive或类似达芬奇的东西
Resolve if you want more you know some
如果您想要更多 请解决 您知道一些
of those more advanced features anyway I
无论如何 在这些更高级的功能中
really appreciate you sticking with me
真的很感激你坚持支持我
and watching this tutorial series go
观看这个系列教程
ahead and like comment subscribe leave
提前并点赞评论订阅休假
your questions below and I hope to see
您的问题如下 我希望看到
you soon in another video tutorial
你很快就会在另一个视频教程中
series
系列